Dear Sir/Madam,

I'm writing in response to the opening for Overseas Division Trade Affairs, which I believe may report to you.

Looking at my CV, you may find out that I don't have experiences particularly relevant to this job. However, I believe that I would be an ideal candidate for this opening since:

- I have extensive backgrounds on logistics and international business (bachelor degree at Foreign Trade University- Vietnam and Master Degree at Newcastle Business School UK).
- I have 4 years experiences working in one of the biggest international project in Vietnam, which involves Japan, Vietnam and other countries (Nghi Son Refinery and Petrochemical LLC).
- I'm a self-discipline person who is proactive and hardworking (which I have learned from my Japanese managers).

I'm really interested in this job in general and working in Japan in particular. I have attached my resume for your review and really hope you can give me a change to interview with you anytime.

Thank you Best regards, Toan Le

LÊ CẢNH TOÀN

Cong Town, Tinh Gia District, Thanh Hoa Province, VN.

Email: lletoan@gmail.com

Contact number: 0904. 874. 459

D.O.B: 30/04/1989

Sex: Male

What I have achieved in:

Education:

- Bachelor of Business: Foreign Trade University (1998-2011). Major: International Business Economics.
- Master of Science (with commendation): Newcastle Business School (2012-2013). Major: Business with International Management.

Career

- Insurance Specialist at **BIDV Insurance Corporation** (16th Floor, Tower A, Vincom City Towers, 191 Ba Trieu, Hanoi, website: www.bic.vn) (2011-2012). Specialised in analysis, my duties were to conduct research on secondary data and competitor products in order to recommend and design a competitive and profitable insurance package. I was also assigned to communicate with agents to introduce the package and get feedback to improve.
- Social and Community- Project leader at Nghi son Refinery & Petrochemical LLC (NSRP) (Nghi son Economic Zone, Tinh gia District, Thanh hoa Province, website: www.nsrp.vn) (2013 until now). Specialised in Strategic Social Investment Section of NSRP, my job is to develop and lead nine projects under four programs, in cooperation with a number of NGOs and government organizations:

o Community Safety Program:

- Emergency Response/First Aid Project (2013-2017); Partner: Thanh Hoa Red Cross; Vietnam Red Cross, Norwegian Red Cross Project Objective: to build capacity for surrounding communities of NSRP Project, particularly children so they will be able to help themselves in an emergency situation (i.e. natural disasters, factory-related emergencies). Main activities: to conduct a research to assess potential risks and recommendation of mitigation activities; to provide emergency response and first aid training courses for community members and students; to provide advanced training for commune officials and necessary equipment/documents for communes; to help community to develop and practice evacuation annually.
- *Traffic Safety Project* (2014-2017); Partner: *AIP*; Main activities: to build capacity for commune officials, teachers, implement awareness activities within community and school and provide small grants for communes and schools to implement traffic safety activities themselves (i.e. road modification, traffic light installation and road-side trimming, competition).

o Education and Trades Training Program:

- Vocational Trades Training Project (2014-2016); Partner: Thanh Hoa Vocational College of Industry; Main activities: to train local affected people basic vocational skills (i.e. sewing, water and electricity, cooking, gardening, industrial cleaning) to help them be able to get a job in the Nghi son Economic Zone.
- On-the-job Training Project (2014-2016); Partner: PTSC Thanh hoa, Nghi son Hotel, Lilama, Anh Phat; Main activities: to provide on-the-job training courses for local affected people at the partner organizations (i.e. welding at Lilama, hotel and room service at Nghi son hotel) with commitment from partner organizations to recruit trainees after successfully completing the courses.
- Education Support Project (2014-2016); Partner: APEX, Tinh Gia Bureau of Education and Training; Main activities: to enhance life-skill training courses for students at five target secondary schools and high schools by building capacity for teachers and support implementation of the course done by the teachers.
- Scholarship Project (2014-2017); Partner: APEX; Tinh Gia Bureau of Education and Training, Main activities: to provide scholarship for qualified students in affected communes.

Community Health Program:

- Community Health Awareness Project (2014-2016); Partner: KENAN, PSI, Tinh Gia Health Center; Main activities: to build capacity for commune health clinic staff and implement awareness activities in community, targeting high-risk diseases in the area identified through KAP survey (i.e. Communicable diseases, STIs, Hygiene).

MSE Support Program:

- **MSE Capacity Building Project** (2014-2017); Partner: *APEX*, Unicom; Main activities: to provide training courses for local MSEs, promote business development in the area and match making between local MSEs and procurement opportunities in the area.
- **Agribusiness Support Project** (2014-2016); Partner: *CHD*; Main activities: to provide hand-on technical support and study tour for community, support community to improve their business efficiency and market linkage, in collaboration with other projects.

These projects aim to mitigate the risks of NSRP Project that would expose to surrounding community while contributing to restore and improve livelihood of communities who lost the land and live surrounding NSRP Project. The success of this program is now becoming the first model of livelihood restoration in Vietnam.

What I'm really good at:

- Background on logistics and international business management.
 - Understanding the background of logistics, particularly import/export (i.e. Incoterms, custom, international payment, etc.)

- Experiences on paper working and management, particularly preparing the templates.
- o Can use advanced design tools including Adobe Photoshop, Adobe illustrator.

• Management skills:

- o Experiences in managing different projects and teams with people from different culture (Vietnam, Japan, Canada, Australia, Philippines)
- Ability to motivate and allocate resources to promote teamwork;
- o Ability to manage conflicts between team members.
- o Ability to think strategically with vision and promote synergy between projects.

• English skills:

- o High level of speaking and writing
- o Ability to produce a professional report and necessary report templates.

My career objectives

My career objective is to look for a long-term job where I'm able to fully demonstrate myself, have a room to raise the idea and opportunity to develop the career . As a hard working person, I don't mind doing field work and travel to different places.

Thank you for spending time reading my CV. I'm looking forward for an interview/discussion so I can demonstrate myself more.